inmyownstyle.com 2018-10-09

# Privacy Policy | In My Own Style

Hello friends!

This website, [_In My Own Style_](https://inmyownstyle.com/)  takes the privacy and security of collected data very seriously.  Whereas this website has always had a policy of never ever sharing your email address or other personal information with third parties,  current internet policies require a more definitive privacy policy statement.

The purpose of this policy is to inform you of the type of personal information this site collects and how it is processed and used, per US/EU Privacy Guidelines.  Here is that statement, in simple terms that everyone can understand.

See my: [Disclosure Policy](https://inmyownstyle.com/disclosure-policy)

**In My Own Style, LLC Cookie and Privacy Policy**

**Effective date:** May 21, 2018 In My Own Style, LLC (Diane Henkler) operates the https://inmyownstyle.com/ website (the “Service”).

This page informs you of my policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you read my blog and/or subscribe by email and the choices you have associated with that data. In My Own Style, LLC will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

There are forms within my site that collect email addresses for the sole purpose of sharing my blog posts and other information that is valuable to my readers. **  By entering your email address into one of these forms**, you are giving your consent for me to send you new post and blog updates via email. You may manage your preferences or unsubscribe at any time via links at the bottom of my emails. These email addresses are never shared with third party sites of any kind.

Your email is also collected when you leave a comment on my site. I use this so I may reply to your comment or question.

**More on Comments:**

When visitors leave comments on my blog, the data shown in the comments form is collected as well as the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

If you leave a comment, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

An anonymized string created from your email address may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you have left comments on In My Own Style, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data I hold about you, including any data you have provided to me. You can also request that I erase any personal data I hold about you. This does not include any data I am obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

_I will never sell, rent, or lease your Personal Data to a third party._

**Media:**  If images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) have been uploaded to In My Own Style. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Embedded content from other websites:  **Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Information In My Own Style Collects from Others** : I may receive information about you from other sources.  For example, you may link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile.  If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile, I will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

**Automatically-Collected Information** :  In My Own Style’s blog framework automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access In My Own Style. For example, when you open a page on In My Own Style,  your IP address is logged, as well as your operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed In My Own Style. I may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

### **Privacy & Cookie Policy**

At https://inmyownstyle.com, I recognize that the privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information I receive and collect when you use and visit https://inmyownstyle.com, and how I safeguard your information.

  * I do not sell data.
  * I do not share data unless compelled by law.
  * I only ask for personal information if it’s needed to provide a service. (For example, I ask for your name and email address when you sign up to receive my blog posts by email. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons** :

I do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit my site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of my features, such as my Email Subscriber’s Only Page. I also use third party advertisements on https://inmyownstyle.com to support my site. These advertisers use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on my site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit my site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to my users based on their visit to my site and/or other sites on the internet. This is generally used for geo-targeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

Ad networks that appear on my site are [ **Google Adsense**](https://www.google.com/adsense) and [ **AdThrive**](http://www.adthrive.com/).

**My email service is Mad Mimi:  **

This service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name (if submitted, it is not required) and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to the [Mad Mimi/GoDaddy privacy policy ](https://www.godaddy.com/Agreements/Privacy.aspx)for further information. If you would like your view and click information to NOT be tracked, please email me at diane@inmyownstyle.com with your request. If you would like to take care of this yourself, click the PREFERENCES button at the bottom of any of my emails.

**Google AdSense & DoubleClick Cookie**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on my blog. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to my readers based on their visit to my blog or other websites on the Internet.You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting the **[Google Ads Settings web page](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/).**
  * As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better.
  * However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others.
  * The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.
  * I suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [ **the About Cookies website**](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.
  * ****[**This page describes how Google uses cookie data**](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/)  from this site.

**More about cookies:**

  * Cookies are small text files that are placed on your device to help the site provide a better user experience.
  * The cookies cannot identify you.
  * In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences and provide anonymized tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.  To opt out of Google Analytics: **[visit this page.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)**

**Retargeting  Ads**

From time to time, In My Own Style may engage in re-marketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to promote my posts and website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

**Affiliate Program Participation**

In My Own Style engages in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

  * **Affiliate links**  
Most of my posts are DIY project tutorials. When applicable I show products I recommend by linking to those items on affiliate sites. These links are a helpful way to show which products I am using in my projects so you know what to look for no matter where you shop.  I make a small percentage of a sale that the retailer pays, never a reader.
  * **RewardStyle:  ** _In My Own Style_  is affiliated by [ **Reward Style** ,](https://www.liketoknow.it/legal/privacy) a program that pays me a small commission if a reader purchases through a link. Example of a RewardStyle link: http://rstyle.me….

  * **Amazon.com:  ** _In My Own Style, LLC_  is a participant in the [ _Amazon Services LLC Associates Program_](https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/), which is an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising (at no additional cost to you) and linking to Amazon.com.  Example of an Amazon link:  https://amzn.to/2KocNbb

  * **Commission Junction:  **In My Own Style is affiliated with CJ, a program that pays me a small commission if a reader purchases through a link on my site. Example of a CJ link: http://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/

**Newsletters/Blog Post Updates/Special Offers**

On In My Own Style, you may subscribe to my posts, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

**Rights Related to Your Personal Information**

https://inmyownstyle.com aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to change your Personal Data, please contact me to make the required changes.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact me.

In certain circumstances, you have the right:

To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you  
To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate  
To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you  
You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to In My Own Style, LLC. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

Please note that I may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe link/button in my emails. You may also notify me at diane@inmyownstyle.com to be removed from my mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information I have about you by submitting a request to diane@inmyownstyle.com

Amend – You may contact me at diane@inmyownsyle.con to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that I erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to diane@inmyownstyle.com.

Please note that I may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

**Sensitive Personal Information**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to In My Own Style. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

In My Own Style does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at diane@inmyownstyle.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**Acceptance of Terms**

Through the use of this website, you are hereby accepting the terms and conditions stipulated within the aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement. If you are not in agreement with these terms and conditions, then you should refrain from further use of this site. In addition, your continued use of this website following the posting of any updates or changes to my terms and conditions shall mean that you are in agreement and acceptance of such changes.

**Contact:**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact: Diane Henkler

By email: diane@inmyownstyle.com  
By visiting this page on our website: https://inmyownstyle.com/privacypolicy

_**Changes to this Privacy Policy**_

_In My Own Style, LLC_ may change this Privacy Policy at any time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy is indicated by the “Last Updated” date at the top of the Privacy Policy. All changes are effective immediately upon posting. Please review this Privacy Policy frequently to stay updated on changes that may affect you. Your continued use of this website signifies your continuing consent to be bound by this Privacy Policy.
